so the book I want to share with you
today is the success of open source by
Steven Weber and this is a book about
the way that open source software arose
within the technology world and then
eventually spread to other domains of
human activity in different market and
governmental settings and the thing that
makes this book so helpful for those of
us trying to create a large scale social
change is that the rise of open-source
software is looked at through the lens
of what is called political economy so
Steven Weber at the time of writing this
was a political economy professor and
researcher at the University of
California in Berkeley and what he did
that I really loved was he looked at the
the way that economic theories presume
that open source software could never be
created and then what was wrong with
those theories as demonstrated by the
actual success of open-source software
so when I read this book I had an
epiphany on the first page about how to
solve the climate crisis so this is a
book that really has some potential for
deep and cathartic insights the thing
for me that really stood out that helped
me have an understanding about dealing
with climate change was a shift in the
way that certain legal definitions are
used so as a technical point open source
software is built on a number of
different licensing agreements and
licensing agreements grow out of the
world of what is called intellectual
property rights which at a deeper level
is about the way that we legally
recognized ownership who owns what and
how and so the thing that Steven Weber
pointed out on page 1 of this book was
that part of the collection of Rights
that an owner has is the right to
exclude others so if I own a piece of
property then I can put a fence around
it and exclude other people from coming
onto my property well in the same way
that I can exclude people from using
something I can create a definition for
why and how people can or cannot use
so what he showed that was really
powerful for me was that open source
software took this right to exclude and
flipped it on its head by saying that
for certain kinds of legal arrangements
this is where the Creative Commons
copyright laws come from for certain
legal arrangements it is possible to say
that if I can exclude anyone from using
this and I will exclude anyone who
doesn't want to share so I will exclude
those who would exclude and when you
take this really powerful bit of legal
jujitsu to its extreme that you get
things like the birth of the entire
sharing economy and so what Steven Weber
does in this book the success of open
source as he explains how the economic
transactions work at the level of a
society so what happens when people come
together and try to create something
really big where ownership is
distributed so Wikipedia is an example
the world owns Wikipedia as an
intellectual commons and it is created
by people contributing to it while
feeling like no one else is ever going
to be able to exclude them or others
from being able to use the material they
created together and so the way that the
legal rights of Wikipedia are set up are
inspired by the legal arrangements for
open source software so in the same way
by changing the way we think about
ownership and collective action to
create really complex socially valuable
things wikipedia open source software or
the sharing economy we begin to see how
we can do a very different approach take
a very different approach to the way
that we create and share things and stop
this hoarding behavior that allows 85
individuals to have more wealth than the
bottom three billion people see that
happens because those who own things
could exclude others from having access
to them but if we set up a system of
legal arrangements where we exclude
those who would hoard things then we can
actually bring that hoarding behavior to
an end and that's one of the things
that's explained and rich
concrete detail with lots of historical
business and technological examples as
well as governmental examples in this
wonderful book so if you want to know
how to hack the financial system and
contribute to the growing sharing
economy and contribute to the commons
that we all depend upon the many
different kinds this is a great how-to
guide for you to understand how to do it
so there you go go to steven webb birds
book the success of open source and hack
the financial system enjoy